Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection AD.MC.002
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971; 585 (Box 1-7)
  - A man wearing a tarbouche with a flywhisk in his hand, sitting on a table. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid116; 548; Studio London Photo, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - A man wearing round glasses and a bow tie. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, 18 February 1933; cuid117; 549; Studio C. Zaphir, Tantah (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Fezes/Tarbouches; Bow Ties; Men; Tanta/Tantah, Egypt; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Signatures; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A man with a mustache wearing circular dark glasses.13.8 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid118; 550; Studio Leon Gherman, Mousky 37, Cairo, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Photographic Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A man wearing a suit with a striped tie, standing with his hands behind his back. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid119; 551; Studio Photo Ramses, Cairo, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Studio Photography; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints
  - A man wearing a white gown and holding prayer beads and a flywhisk, sitting in a garden. Arabic text on reverse: Zahle, Jebel Lubnan, Lebanon. 13.6 x 8.4 cm, 6 August 1946; cuid120; 552; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Facial Hair; Men; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Gardens; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Arabic Writing; Prayer Beads; Lebanon; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Zahle, Beqaa, Lebanon; Hats
  - A group of boys at school, one sits at a typewriter. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid121; 553; El Shazly, Saad (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Group Portraits; Hats; Typewriters; Fezes/Tarbouches; Photographic Prints; Teachers; Qena, Egypt; Men; Schools/Education; Boys; Arabic Writing; Students; Machines; Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Typewriters; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A man in a dark suit with a short mustache. 13.6 x 9.1 cm, Undated; cuid122; 554; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Individual Portraits
  - A group of men wearing suits and tarbouches at a ceremony. 8.4 x 13.9 cm, Undated; cuid123; 555; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Fezes/Tarbouches; Canes/Walking Sticks; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Audiences/Spectators; Photographic Prints; Events/Occasions; Ceremonies; Girls; Children; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group pose in a home setting. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid124; 556; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Photographic Prints; Houses; Women; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Egypt; Group Portraits
  - A man wearing a dark three-piece suit and patterned tie. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid125; 557; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Individual Portraits; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Arabic Writing; Signatures; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Facial Hair
  - A group of boy scouts and their teachers. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid126; 558; El Shazly, Saad (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Uniforms; Arabic Writing; Children; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Scouts; Schools/Education; Fezes/Tarbouches; Buildings; Boys; Qena, Egypt; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Men
  - A couple, the woman is seated in a high back chair, the man sits on the arm. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid127; 559; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Egypt; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Furnishings; Women; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - An oval cropped portrait of a woman wearing a black dress, against a painted backdrop. 13.4 x 8.1 cm, Undated; cuid128; 560; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - A man wearing a black suit, resting on a table and standing in front of a curtain. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, 1921; cuid129; 561; Studio Badr (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Furnishings; Men; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Egypt; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A boy wearing a tarbouche, leaning on the back of a chair. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid130; 562; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Egypt; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Boys; Painted Backdrops; Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - An oval cropped portrait of a man seated in a chair wearing a light suit with a bow tie. 14.1 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid131; 563; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Facial Hair; Men; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties
  - An Armenian man wearing a dark suit and patterned tie. 13.6 x 8.8 cm, 21 May 1928; cuid132; 564; Studio Photo Aïda, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Armenian Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A wood supply warehouse (depot de bois) entrance. Egyptian postal stamp on reverse. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, 2 October 1958; cuid133; 565; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Architecture; Postal Stamps; Buildings; Arabic Writing; Construction; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Postcards; French Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads
  - A man in a white shirt and a young woman wearing a checked dress, surrounded by flowers (linked ref161). 13.6 x 8.9 cm, 6 December 1970; cuid134; 566; Studio Torkum, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Group Portraits
  - A man wearing a turtleneck sweater and a woman wearing a white dress. Studio background with flowers (linked ref160). 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 10 December 1969; cuid135; 567; Studio Torkum, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Group Portraits
  - An oval cropped portrait of a man wearing a suit with a short tie and a tarbouche.13.6 x 8.6 cm, 10 (?) 1920; cuid136; 568; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A family group at the beach in Sidi Bechir, Tunis. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, 10 August 1951; cuid137; 569; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Children; Girls; Boys; Beaches; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; French Writing; Tunis, Tunisia; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
  - Four men wearing suits, sitting on the grass in a park. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid138; 570; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Men; Parks; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - A teacher with his students posing in front of a painted backdrop. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid139; 571; Studio Photo Moderne, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Teachers; Girls; Schools/Education; Boys; Children; Schools/Education; Students; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Facial Hair
  - A studio portrait of two women and a man wearing a bow tie. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; cuid140; 572; Studio Photo Moderne, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Alexandria, Egypt; Bow Ties; Group Portraits
  - A young man wearing a uniform, seated surrounded by props, holding a rod in his hands. 14.0 x 9.1 cm, Undated; cuid141; 573; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Uniforms; Men; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers
  - An Armenian band. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, October 1924; cuid142; 574; Studio Photo Aïda, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Brass Instruments; Musical Instruments; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair
  - An Armenian family group, a couple (Mr. and Mrs. Asfian) with children. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, 1929; cuid143; 575; Studio Royal Photo, Tournon, France; Tafalla, J. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; France; Armenian Writing; Photographic Prints; Children; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Boys; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A woman wearing a dress with white flowers and a hat. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid144; 576; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Individual Portraits; Bags/Purses; Jewelry; Studio Photography; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Arabic Writing; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Women
  - Two men in uniforms with a small potted plant in between them. 13.6 x 9.0 cm, Undated; cuid145; 577; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Studio Photography; Clocks/Watches; Men; Police; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Medals/Insignia
  - A fade out portrait of a man wearing a dark suit with tie, looking directly at the camera. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid146; 578; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Men; Studio Photography; Egypt; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A group of men in bathing suits on a wooden deck. 8.6 x 13.6 cm, Undated; cuid147; 579; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Arabic Writing; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Egypt; Men; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair
  - A young couple reading a book against a painted backdrop. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid148; 580; Studio London, Cairo, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Cairo, Egypt; Women; Painted Backdrops; Men; Books; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Group Portraits
  - A young man in a suit and tie, with a handkerchief in his pocket. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid149; 581; Studio Badr (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Men; Arabic Writing; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares
  - A woman with long hair and a long dark dress, posing in front of a table. 12.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid150; 582; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Egypt; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Individual Portraits; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - An Armenian couple, the man is seated in a ornate chair. Armenian text on reverse: My beloved sister. Receive this photograph from Mrs. Mariam Asufian's family for the unforgettable memories. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, 10 September 1928; cuid151; 583; Studio Dydyian, Kokkinia (Greece) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Greece; Armenian Writing; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women; Men; Nikaia, Attica, Greece; Alexandria, Egypt; Signatures; Painted Backdrops; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Carpets/Rugs
  - A young man leaning on a pedestal, wearing a suit and tarbouche in front of painted backdrop. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid152; 584; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fezes/Tarbouches; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Children; Boys; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A man in a dark suit leaning on the back of a chair. Postcard sent from Germany. 13.2 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid153; 586; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; German Writing; Postal Stamps; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Arabic Writing; Germany; Postcards; Al Darb al Aḩmar, Egypt; Signatures
  - Three men wearing party hats, playing various musical instruments and using studio props. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid154; 587; Studio Photo (Th.) Canton, 24 Bld Saad Zaghloul, Alexandrie (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Costumes; Alexandria, Egypt; Men; Toys; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - A young woman wearing a long skirt sitting on the grass in front of some foliage. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, 22 April 1957; cuid155; 588; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Parks; Gelibolu, Turkey; Gardens; Women; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
  - Two men on a prop boat named Sphinx. Studio background with trees and the moon. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid156; 589; Studio Sedefgian Photographe, Place Ataba-el-Khadra, Cairo, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes/Tarbouches; Boats/Ships; Painted Backdrops; Men; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair
  - A woman wearing a striped white dress and necklace holding onto a curtain. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid157; 590; Studio L. Missak, Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Individual Portraits; Women; Photographic Prints; Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Jewelry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Carpets/Rugs
  - A woman wearing a long beaded necklace sitting on a bench with a bouquet in her hand. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid158; 591; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Women; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Studio Photography
  - A woman wearing a patterned chiffon dress with a pearl necklace sitting on a chair. (Same table and background from ref187 and ref223. 13.6 x 8.5 cm), Undated; cuid159; 592; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Women; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Photographic Prints
  - A woman wearing a satin dress and pearl necklace, sitting in a chair with a letter in her hands. Same table and backdrop from (ref186 and ref223). 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid160; 593; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Egypt; Furnishings; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops
  - A man in a Bedouin costume with a sword, against a painted backdrop. Same studio backdrop as ref190. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Circa 1922; cuid161; 594; Studio Vincent Photo Egyptienne, Rue Abdine No. 6, Caire (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Weapons; Furnishings; Regional/National Dress; Swords/Knives; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Costumes; Egypt
  - A man in traditional Upper Egyptian clothes with a boy standing next to him. 14.0 x 9.1 cm, Undated; cuid162; 595; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Men; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings; Regional/National Dress; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Boys; Turbans; Group Portraits
  - A young man with a mustache in a Bedouin costume, holding a a sword. (Same studio backdrop as ref188). 13.7 x 8.7 cm, 1922; cuid163; 596; Studio Vincent Photo Egyptienne, Rue Abdine No. 6, Caire (Egypt); Jacques, Vincent P.; Studio Photo Egyptienne, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Regional/National Dress; Egypt; Costumes; Swords/Knives; Arabic Writing; Weapons; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Painted Backdrops; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - A woman wearing a beaded necklace, sitting on a bench with her feet on a cushion. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid164; 597; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Women; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewelry; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Carpets/Rugs
  - A young woman wearing a heart-shaped necklace. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid165; 598; Cairo Studio, TH. Kofler (Egypt); Kofler, Theodor (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography
  - A woman wearing a dark dress with circles, reclining on a chaise longue. 8.5 x 13.6 cm, Undated; cuid166; 599; Studio Photo Ramses, Cairo, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Cairo, Egypt; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Studio Photography
  - A woman wearing a black dress sitting on a bench. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, 1908; cuid167; 600; Studio - Isidore (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Clocks/Watches; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Arabic Writing; Women; Individual Portraits; Egypt; Carpets/Rugs
  - A boy standing in front of some potted plants and a watering can. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; cuid168; 601; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Gardens; Individual Portraits; Boys; Egypt
  - Two women talking under a parasol on the beach.. 8.8 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid169; 602; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Jewelry; Gelatin Silver Prints; Clocks/Watches; Egypt; Bathing Suits/Swimsuits; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Beaches
  - Two girls wearing light colored dresses. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, 1951; cuid170; 603; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Children; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Schools/Education; Egypt; Photographic Prints
  - A woman in a dark dress holding a small white flower. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid171; 604; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Individual Portraits; Egypt
  - A man in traditional Upper Egyptian clothing, leaning on a white ornate table. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid172; 605; Studio Photo Ramses, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Facial Hair; Men; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Egypt; Facial Hair; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turbans
  - A girl in an Ottoman style dancing costume in a garden. 13.1 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid173; 606; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Egypt; Dancing; Individual Portraits; Girls; Regional/National Dress; Children; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Costumes; Gardens
  - Two women posing in an open-top car, a 1928 Citröen Type B 14, Sport Caddy. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated; cuid174; 607; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Cars/Trucks; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Photographic Prints; Women; Group Portraits; Transportation
  - A man sitting on chair with crossed legs, wearing a suit and bow tie. 13.3 x 8.6 cm, Undated; cuid175; 608; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Bow Ties; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Egypt; Men; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Furnishings
  - A couple holding hands, the woman wears a pearl necklace. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid176; 609; Studio Badr (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Men; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Egypt; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A group portrait with a man, woman and three boys. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; cuid177; 610; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Women; Boys; Egypt; Children; Fezes/Tarbouches; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A woman in a light colored dress sitting in a chair and leaning on a table. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid178; 611; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Jewelry; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Egypt; Women; Individual Portraits
  - A boy on a tricycle wearing a tarbouche. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid179; 612; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gardens; Photographic Prints; Bicycles/Tricycles; Arabic Writing; Individual Portraits; Boys; Children; Fezes/Tarbouches
  - A hand painted photo of a man in military uniform standing in front of a prop with a plant on it. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, Undated; cuid180; 614; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Men; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - Three women wearing dresses and headbands. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated; cuid181; 615; Studio Aziz & Dores, Photographes, 3 Rue de L'Hopital Grec, Alexandrie (Alexandria, Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Group Portraits; Women; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Alexandria, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings
  - A woman wearing a dark colored headscarf, posing with three children in a garden. 14.1 x 8.9 cm, Undated; cuid182; 616; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Photographic Prints; Egypt; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Gardens; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Boys; Girls; Women; Group Portraits
  - Two women and two girls having a picnic on the beach. 14.1 x 9.2 cm, Undated; cuid183; 617; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Girls; Hats; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children; Women; Beaches; Picnic; Group Portraits
  - A group of men posing next to and on a train at El Minia (Minya) train station. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Circa 1867; cuid184; 618; Feldman, I.; Studio Feldmann, Photo Minia (Egypt); Photo Minia (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Ceremonies; Men; Events/Occasions; Photographic Prints; Minya, Egypt; Trains; Group Portraits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Railways; Transportation; Facial Hair
  - A group of eight men in front of a painted backdrop. 8.4 x 13.5 cm, 13 February 1924; cuid185; 619; Studio Bridge, 6 Bridge Road, Woolston (England) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Photographic Prints; Bow Ties; Painted Backdrops; Group Portraits; Southampton, England, UK; Men; Studio Photography; Arabic Writing; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Furnishings
  - A man in military uniform with some medals, standing on a street with buildings in the background. 13.2 x 8.6 cm, 1 July 1945; cuid186; 620; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Outdoors; Buildings; Medals/Insignia; Arabic Writing; Facial Hair
  - A man wearing a suit with a bow tie and flower. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, 1930; cuid187; 621; Studio - Photo Venus, 3 Rue Emad-El-Dine, Ataba, Le Caire (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Ataba, Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Men; Signatures; Bow Ties; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography
  - A family group, a woman, girl and two boys wearing suits. 13.5 x 8.2 cm, Undated; cuid188; 622; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 20)